Another useful feature of
Excel is the ability to display
information in chart format.
Charts can be useful because
they allow you to present
information in a graphical format.
So people can see at a glance, the
variation in sales or variation in income.
And if there's any concerns they can
see the difference between the best
month sales or the worst month sales.
So this can allow people to see
that rather than just looking at
data on a worksheet, seeing it
in a graphical representation can
point out things that may not be
as clear within the data itself.
So the first thing you need to do is
you need to select the information that
you're going to create the chart from.
And what I'm going to do here is I'm
going to create a chart to show the
total sales for all the products.
So the first thing I need to do is
I need to select the product data.
So if I click in the product cell,
A1, and click and hold and drag
that down to "weekend experience".
Now because the information that I need
to create the chart is not alongside
each other, so there are quite a lot of
columns between the product and total
sales, to select non-adjacent columns,
I need to hold down the control key.
So if I press and hold the control key,
select the total sales heading, and then
drag that down to the weekend experience
figure, and then release the control key.
You can see that I have now
selected those two columns.
So from there, we need
to create the chart.
So to do that, we go up to the insert tab
and I click on the insert tab and we need
to navigate along to the chart section.
Now there are various icons within
here, so you can add specific
types of charts so that one there
would be for a column or bar chart,
line chart, pie chart, and so on.
For this instance, I'm just going to
select the recommended chart icon.
So if I click on that, and that
brings up the insert chart dialog box.
Now a good thing here is it's given me
a graphical representation of what the
chart will look like when I select it.
So that would be a bar chart, a pie
chart, a column chart, and a funnel chart.
And the one I'm going to select
for this is a column chart.
So once I've selected that if I select
OK, that then now creates the chart.
So we've now created a chart so the
total sales for each of the products.
So you've got the one hour, two
hour, half the experience, full day
experience and weekend experience.
And just to check, you can see if you
look at the actual data, you can see that
that is the data that's been selected.
It has been highlighted by bounding
boxes around the information.
So once we've got that, we
have now inserted our chart.